{
    "id": "9a878f8eff894153876fc7aa8274ced3",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "‘Where is Raj?’ ‘He ……………………….. out.’",
            "description": "When just means a moment ago, it can be used with a present perfect or simple past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "just went",
                "has just gone",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. what you mean.",
            "description": "Know cannot be used in the progressive form.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "am knowing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It’s time we ……………………….. a new car.",
            "description": "We use a past tense after it’s time with a present meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "buy",
                "bought",
                "had bought"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It took me months …………………………. to know her.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "getting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………… ten minutes ago.",
            "description": "Left is the past tense of leave.",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Those who know the answer should …………………………….. their hands.",
            "description": "Before an object, we use raise.",
            "answers": [
                "raise",
                "rise",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………….. from her seat.",
            "description": "Rise can mean get up.",
            "answers": [
                "raised",
                "rose",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They ……………………….. him with an iron rod.",
            "description": "Struck is the past tense of strike.",
            "answers": [
                "striked",
                "struck",
                "struk"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The bullet ………………………… the policeman in the right arm.",
            "description": "Wounded is the past tense of wound.",
            "answers": [
                "wound",
                "wounded"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They ………………………………. the yarn into a ball.",
            "description": "Wound is the past tense of wind.",
            "answers": [
                "winded",
                "wound",
                "wounded"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. the boxes on the table.",
            "description": "To lay something is to put it or set it down.",
            "answers": [
                "Lay",
                "Lie",
                "Lain"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The tiles were ……………………… in a geometric pattern.",
            "description": "Laid is the past and past participle form of lay.",
            "answers": [
                "lied",
                "laid",
                "lain"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}